
         
         <!--page 4 (sb_08) -->
         
         <div type="article" n="1.1">
            
            <head>Dublin And District Motor<lb/> Cycle Club Had Day Out</head>
            <div type="lead">
               <p rend="bold"><hi rend="case (allcaps)">CONGRATULATIONS</hi> to <name type="org">the Dublin and District Motor Cycle <lb/>
                  Club</name> whose <name type="race">International Moto Cross meeting</name> on Saturday <lb/>
                  last was one of the most entertaining fixtures of the season. <lb/>
                  the course at <placeName>Redbog</placeName> was ideally suited for this sport and many <lb/>
                  of <name type="org">the English works riders</name>described it as one of the <lb/>
                  best in <placeName> Europe</placeName>. <lb/>
               </p>
               
            </div>
            <div type="section">
               <cb/>
               <p>In the light og such an enthusi-<lb/>astic reception it is now very much <lb/>
                  more than a possibility that next<lb/> year's meeting will be included on <lb/>
                  the <name type="race">world championship</name> table with <lb/> the result that we may have a <lb/>
                  unique invasion of manufacturers <lb/> teams including leading English<lb/>
                  and Continental exponents.<lb/></p>
               <p>As expected the <hi rend="case (allcaps)">B.S.A</hi> and the Dot<lb/>
                  nominees made a clean sweep in<lb/> the last three <name type="race">scratch races</name> on Satur-<lb/>
                  day last but quite a few names were made by Irishmen whose pre-<lb/>
                  vious experience was gained from <lb/> dabbling in other branches of the<lb/>
                  game together with a mere handful <lb/> of scrambles.<lb/></p>
               <p>Perhaps the most impressive was <lb/> <persName>Harry O'Reilly's</persName> son, <persName>Frank</persName>, who<lb/>
                  rode his <objectName type="motorcycle">Lightweight Tandon</objectName> with <lb/> an unbounded exuberance which <lb/>
                  made quite a few of the stars, and <lb/> in particular <persName>Bill Barugh</persName> og the <lb/>
                  <name type="org">Dot team</name>, sit up and take note <lb/>
                  After figuring prominently in the <lb/> qualifying heat <persName>Frank</persName> put every- <lb/>
                  thing he knew into the final and <lb/> going into the lead on the third lap <lb/>
                  he stayed in front until the last half mile where he was headed by <lb/>
                  <persName>Eric Williams</persName> on the <objectName type="motorcycle">Mountjoy<lb/>
                  entered Ariel.</objectName><lb/></p>
            </div>
            <div type= "section"> <head rend="bold"> <hi rend="case (allcaps)"> FIGURED PROMINENTLY</hi></head>
               <p rend="bold"> If he continues to improve at <lb/> the present rate there is little <lb/>
                  doubt that <persName>Frank O'Reilly</persName> could <lb/> turn out to be a really top class <lb/>
                  Moto Cross and Road Racing star <lb/> He has certainly put his Grasstrack <lb/>
                  experience to great use and his long distance road racing debut on the Brian Somers <hi rend="case (allcaps)">B.S.A</hi> at this<lb/>
                  year's <name type="race">Skerries "100"</name> gave some indication of the Dubliner's ability</p>
               <p>The <persName>Williams</persName> brothers, <persName ref="#IW">Ian</persName> and <lb/>
                  <persName>Eric</persName> also caught the eye on Saturday <lb/> last and both of them figured promi-<lb/>
                  nently in the awards list. Indeed <lb/> were it not for the fact that <persName>Eric</persName><lb/>
                  had shown such a terrific improve-<lb/>ment in his riding he could never <lb/> have overhauled <persName>Frank O'Reilly</persName> in<lb/>
                  order to capture the <name type="race">Freeman <cb/> Trophy</name> in the general handicap final.</p>
               <p><persName ref="#IW">Ian</persName>, who rode at several <name type="race">cross <lb/> Channel meetings</name> last season was <lb/>
                  the fastest Irishman of the dat as <lb/> he took <persName>Ted Barret's</persName> other <objectName type="motorcycle">Ariel</objectName> into <lb/>
                  fourth place in the <name type="race">Senior scratch <lb/> race</name> despite a heavy tumbe en route<lb/>
                  He also occupied a similar position <lb/> in the general handicap and con <lb/> sidering that he was riding off such <lb/>
                  a short mark of one and a half <lb/> minutes he did extremely well to get the flag so near to <persName>Brian Stone- <lb/>bridge</persName> the <hi rend="case (allcaps)">B.S.A</hi> expert.<lb/> </p>
               <p>The evergreen <persName>Ernie Lyons</persName> gave <lb/> the huge crowds plenty to enthuse <lb/>
                  over in the 250 <name type="race">c.c. event</name> and his <lb/> fourth position behind three of <name type="org">the <lb/>
                  Dot men</name> and in front of another <lb/> of them calls for honourable men-<lb/>tion Unfortunately <persName>Freddie Dixon</persName><lb/>
                  who was also expected to do well in <lb/> the same event broke his frame on<lb/>
                  the first lap and took no further <lb/> part in the proceedings</p>
             </div>
             <div type="section"> <head rend="case (allcaps)"><hi rend="bold">NORTHERN SUCCESSES</hi></head>
               <p rend="bold">Several Ulster riders hit the <lb/> headlines during the afternoon.<lb/>
                  the most successful of them being <lb/> <persName>Alex McFarland Woods</persName> from <placeName>Bel-
                  <lb/>fast</placeName> who finished fourth to <name type="org">the <hi rend="case (allcaps)">B.S.A.</hi> team</name> in the <name type="race">350 c.c. scratch<lb/>
                  race</name> fifth to <persName ref="#IW">Ian Williams</persName> and the <lb/> same trio in the <name type="race">Senior event</name> and <lb/>
                  sixth in the genereal handicap all on a <name type="motorcycle">Junior 'Gold Star"</name>.</p>
               <p><persName>Alan Bradshaw</persName> made news with his <lb/> <name type="motorcycle">Francis-Barnett</name> when taking a very <lb/>
                  creditable sixth in the opening en-<lb/> counter and he finished up the day <lb/> as eight man home in the general <lb/>
                  handicap with a comparatively <lb/> short allowance of one lap.</p>
                <p><name type="race">The Car Trials</name> season gets into its <lb/> stride this weekend when <name type="org">the Lein-<lb/>
                   ster Motor Club</name> holds it <name type="race">Vigzol Cup <lb/> meeting</name> over a 60 mile course start-<lb/>
                   ing in the <placeName>Phoenix Park</placeName> at <time>3 p.m</time><lb/> on Saturday. Navigation by Ordnance <lb/>
                   Survey sheets No. 16 and 13 will play <lb/> an important part in prodeedings <lb/> and references by the old and new <lb/>
                   grid system will be supplied to com<lb/>petitors</p>
                <p>Sunday's <name type="race">Circuit of Clare</name> T <damage rend="missing text"/> <lb/> which starts from <placeName>Limerick</placeName> at <damage rend="missing text"/> <lb/>
                   a.m. wukk narj tge beginning <damage type="tape">of the</damage> <lb/> <name type="race">Hewison Trophy competition</name> <damage type="tape"> and</damage><lb/>
                   because of this all leading <placename><damage type="tape">Dublin</damage></placename><lb/>
                   and <name type="race">Provincial</name> enthusiasts are ex-<lb/>pected to make the journey for this<lb/>
                   well supported fixture.</p>
            </div>
         </div>   
            
         
         
      </body>
